

Andrea Buran, product design lead, at your service.

I design and craft digital services and products that help people do things better.

Born on the 16<sup>th</sup> of April 1985, in San Donà di Piave, Italy. Live in Istanbul, Turkey.

Speak Italian (mother tongue), English (fluent) and a little Turkish (learning in progress).

Over the last ten years, have been driving and crafting projects with industry leaders in automotive, culture, e-commerce, finance, human resources, telco, and tourism.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

Product Department Manager, Aug 2019-Present Product Manager + Designer, May 2019-Aug 2019 Kolay, Istanbul, Turkey

Kolay is a SaaS platform focused on HR management for SMEs, serving more than 1.400 companies and 200.000 users.

#### **Product Department Manager**

Define and plan product goals, strategies, and roadmaps. ¶ Articulate, share, and back up conceptual and directional decisions. ¶ Facilitate discussions and alignments within Product and with other departments. ¶ Coordinate the work of managers, designers, and testers through sprint cycles. ¶ Set and improve Product's processes, methodologies, and tools. ¶ Mentor, coach and inspire the Product's department members, and foster and grow a design culture within Kolay.

### **Product Manager**

Own and follow products and features to ease the work of Kolay's users, from definition to release and beyond. ¶ Discuss and collaborate with different departments to identify, understand, define, and align on business and product goals, problems, and outcomes. ¶ Conduct quantitative and/or qualitative research to discover, understand and define users' needs, problems, and outcomes. ¶ Be on top of the stream of user feedback by investigating discoveries and framing them as actionable problems, ready to be solved. ¶ Interpret, digest, synthesize, and document learnings, insights, and conclusions, and share and champion them with others. ¶ Inform and define product roadmaps, and identify, prioritize, and scope the right problems and opportunities to focus on next. ¶ Coordinate with Product and Development to scope, phase, and plan the designing and developing of the chosen solutions in sprint cycles. ¶ Support and guide designers, developers, and testers during releases.

# **Product Designer**

Ideate, explore, and define high-level solutions to problems through requirement documents and quick high-level/lowfidelity prototypes. ¶ Choose the right solutions to further refine, and design and detail them iterating through from low- to high-fidelity prototypes. ¶ Validate the solutions with users and stakeholders and iterate on them in response to the feedback received. ¶ Define product requirements and acceptance criteria. ¶ Test and ensure the release of highquality solutions. ¶ Set and use Kolay's web and mobile design systems, and maintain and extend them by scaling and iterating on their patterns and components.



Designer

Design Leader, Jan 2018–Apr 2019 Senior Visual Designer, May 2016–Dec 2018

I-AM Digital, Istanbul, Turkey

Conceived and designed digital services and products across multiple channels and platforms following a user-centric approach. ¶ Generated, communicated, and discussed strategies, concepts, detailed designs, and design rationales, both verbally and visually, with stakeholders and clients. ¶ Translated design strategies and concepts into detailed interaction and visual designs. ¶ Validated the designs with users, stakeholders, and clients, and iterated on them through from low- to high-fidelity prototypes. ¶ Created comprehensive and cohesive design systems by following an atomic design approach. ¶ Led and guided fellow team members throughout the user experience and interface design phases of various projects. ¶ Mentored, coached, and inspired a talented team of designers by giving constructive feedback, critiques, and food for thought. ¶ Set and improved the studio design processes, methodologies, and tools. ¶ Tailored the design processes to project needs and goals, and evaluate and discuss their requirements, efforts, and risks.

Visual Designer, May 2014-Apr 2016

Fjord, Istanbul, Turkey

Conceived and designed digital services and products across multiple channels and platforms following a user-centric approach. ¶ Generated design strategies and concepts and translated them into detailed interaction and visual designs. ¶ Communicated and discussed research findings, concepts, designs, and rationales, both verbally and visually. ¶ Validated the designs with users, stakeholders, and clients, and iterated on them through from low- to high-fidelity prototypes. ¶ Defined and detailed interaction and visual design documentation and guidelines.

Visual & Interaction Designer, Jul 2009–May 2014 Self-employed, Venice, Italy

Conceived, designed, crafted and developed commercial and self-initiated digital and non-digital communication artifacts, from definition to release and beyond.

Visual & Interaction Designer, Nov 2010–Jul 2012

Wolfgang Scheppe Associates, Venice, Italy

Researched, conceived, designed and developed varied communication strategies, concepts and artifacts, from corporate identities to reports, books, videos, and sites.

Andrea Buran

Designer

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Visual Communication and Multimedia

**graduate degree, 110/110 cum laude**, full marks and honors Oct 2007–Apr 2010, Faculty of Arts and Design, IUAV University of Venice, Italy

#### Industrial Design (with a focus on communication)

undergraduate degree, 110/110, full marks

Oct 2004–Nov 2007, Faculty of Arts and Design, IUAV University of Venice, Italy

## **TALENTS + SKILLS**

#### **User-centric approach**

Eager to empathize with users to understand their problems, needs, and outcomes. Able to translate business goals in product outcomes and relate them to user outcomes to drive a positive change in user behavior.

### Leadership and direction

Well-organized at handling projects from kick-off to release, and beyond. ¶ At ease in guiding, mentoring, coaching, and inspiring fellow team members.

## Strategy and concept generation

Strong in generating strategies and concepts in response to users' needs and businesses' goals, and within the requirements and constraints of projects.

## **Experimental approach**

Resort to prototyping to make solutions tangible, validate them with fellow team members, stakeholders, and users, and iterate on them in response to the feedback received.

## Cross-platform and device knowledge

Have been crafting applications for multiple platforms (Android, iOS, Web) and devices (mobile, tablet, desktop), adopting the appropriate design principles and patterns.

# Design software

Well-experienced in **Keynote**, **Illustrator**, **Indesign**, **Photoshop**, **After Effects**, **Principle**, and **Invision**. ¶ Fond and happy of designing with **Figma**, **Sketch**, and **Zeplin** lately.

## **Passion for coding**

Love coding and hands-on in front-end web development.  $\P$  Fluent in **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **SCSS** and proficient in XML, XPath and XSLT.  $\P$  Have basic knowledge of Javascript and Processing.

